confetti.co.uk 2015-12-12

# Privacy Policy | Confetti.co.uk

Confetti Celebrations Limited (“Confetti”) is totally committed to protecting the privacy of our site visitors and customers. The Confetti team members are customers themselves of other Internet sites and fully appreciate and respect the importance of privacy on the Internet. We will not disclose information about our customers to third parties except where it is part of providing a service to you – e.g. arranging for a product to be sent to you, or carrying out credit and other security checks.

## How We Use Your Information

This privacy policy tells you what to expect when Confetti Celebrations Ltd. collects personal information. It applies to information we collect about:

  * visitors to our website
  * customers who place orders with us
  * people who call us
  * vistors or customers who send us reviews, compliments or complaints
  * people who use our services, e.g. use our forums, planning tools or subscribe to our newsletters
  * people who enter any of our competitions
  * job applicants and our current and former employees

If we collect your personal information for any of these reasons, we may share your email address with registered Confetti suppliers from time to time.

### Visitors to Our Website

When someone visits [confetti.co.uk](http://www.confetti.co.uk/) we collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. We collect this information in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website. We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any personally identifying information from any source. If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through our website, we will be up front about this. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it.

### Customers Who Place Orders with Us

When a customer places an order with us, we collect address and payment information in order to process the order and dispatch the goods. This information is also kept indefinately, to allow us to deal with any issues in the relation to the order, or to process a return or replacement of any goods.

### People Who Call Us

When you call Confetti customer services we collect Calling Line Identification (CLI) information. We use this information to help improve its efficiency and effectiveness.

### Visitors or Customers Who Send a Review, Compliment or Compaint to Us

When we receive a review, compliment or complaint from a person we keep the information we receive within emails. This normally contains the identity of the complainant and any other individuals involved.

We will only use the personal information we collect to process the complaint and to check on the level of service we provide. We may also use this information on our testimonial or review pages.

### People Who Use Confetti Services

Confetti offers various services to visitors. For example, we offer planning tools, provide a [forum](http://forums.confetti.co.uk/ "forum") for visitors to communicate with each other and distribute electronic newsletters and emails containing product offers. Information stored within the planning tools and forums may be used to tailor the experience that you receive to highlight products and services that are likely to be most appropriate for you. We use a third party to manage to sending of some emails, but they are only allowed to use the information to send out our emails.

Users may, from time to time, receive information from us about new features, new services, news and special offers. If a user takes advantage of special offers made by our marketing partners, we may, with the user’s consent, transfer the user’s personal information to them.

We have to hold the details of the people who have requested our services in order to provide it. However, we only use these details to provide the service the person has requested and for other closely related purposes. For example, we might use a person’s wedding date to work out when they are likely to be interested in looking at table decorations. When people do subscribe to our services, they can cancel their subscription at any time and are given an easy way of doing this.

### Job Applicants, Current and Former Confetti Employees

When individuals apply to work at Confetti, we will only use the information they supply to us to process their application and to monitor recruitment statistics. Where we want to disclose information to a third party, for example where we want to take up a reference or obtain a ‘disclosure’ from the Criminal Records Bureau we will not do so without informing them beforehand unless the disclosure is required by law.

Personal information about unsuccessful candidates will be held for 12 months after the recruitment exercise has been completed, it will then be destroyed or deleted. We retain de-personalised statistical information about applicants to help inform our recruitment activities, but no individuals are identifiable from that data.

Once a person has taken up employment with the Confetti, we will compile a file relating to their employment. The information contained in this will be kept secure and will only be used for purposes directly relevant to that person’s employment. Once their employment with Confetti has ended, we will retain the file in accordance with the requirements of our retention schedule and then delete it.

## Use of Cookies by Confetti

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site.

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

Each cookie used on the Confetti website can be categorised into one or more of the following categories:

  * Strictly Necessary Cookies
  * Functionality Cookies
  * Performance Cookies

### Strictly Necessary Cookies

#### Content Management System

**Names** : ASP.NET_SessionId, SessionTracker, ASPSESSIONIDSCBDCARQ, comment_author_fc6c5f13d71212b6b52e11ebb43da857

**Purpose** : These cookies are used internally by the content management systems that the Confetti website runs on.

#### E-commerce System

**Names** : PHPSESSID, ORDNO, ServerID, SUB00001_SBASKET, priamGUID

**Purpose** : These cookies are used internally by the e-commerce system that the Confetti website runs on. These cookies also help to keep track of which products have been added to a customer’s online shopping basket.

#### Stationery Customisation System

**Names** : StationeryBag

**Purpose** : This cookie helps to keep track of any choices you make when customising stationery on our website.

#### Forum System

**Names** : phpbb3_qjonx_u, phpbb3_qjonx_k, phpbb3_qjonx_sid

**Purpose** : These cookies are used internally by the forum system that the Confetti forum runs on.

#### User Login

**Names** : WelcomeToConfetti, ASPConfetti, ASPConfettiOld, at, appNameAuth

**Purpose** : These cookies allow users to login to the website and to maintain this logged in status across the various systems that the website comprises.

#### Live Chat Support

**Names** : __lc.server.1039062, __lc.visitor_id.1039062

**Purpose** : These cookies are required to allow our live chat support service to function correctly.

**More information** : [Click here for an overview of privacy at our Live Chat provider](http://www.livechatinc.com/privacy-policy/).

### Performance Cookies

#### Google Analytics

**Names** : _utma, _utmb, _utmc, _utmz

**Purpose** : These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

**More information** : [Click here for an overview of privacy at Google](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html "External link").

### YouTube Cookies

We embed videos from our official YouTube channel using YouTube’s privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode. To find out more please visit [YouTube’s embedding videos information page](http://www.google.com/support/youtube/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=171780 "External link").

### Removing and Disabling Cookies

If you do not wish to accept cookies on to your machine you can disable them by adjusting the settings on your browser. However this will affect the functionality of the websites you visit, including the functionality of the Confetti website.

## Complaints or Queries

We try to meet the highest standards when collecting and using personal information. For this reason, we take any complaints we receive about this very seriously. We encourage people to bring it to our attention if they think that our collection or use of information is unfair, misleading or inappropriate. We would also welcome any suggestions for improving our procedures.

This privacy notice was drafted with brevity and clarity in mind. It does not provide exhaustive detail of all aspects of Confetti’s collection and use of personal information. However, we are happy to provide any additional information or explanation needed. Any requests for this should be sent to the address below.

## Access to Personal Information

We try to be as open as we can be in terms of giving people access to their personal information. Individuals can find out if we hold any personal information by making a ‘subject access request’ under the Data Protection Act 1998. If we do hold information about you we will:

  * give you a description of it;
  * tell you why we are holding it;
  * tell you who it could be disclosed to; and
  * let you have a copy of the information in an intelligible form.

To make a request to Confetti for any personal information we may hold you need to put the request in writing addressing it to our Customer Services department, or writing to the address provided below.

If you agree, we will try to deal with your request informally, for example by providing you with the specific information you need over the telephone.

If we do hold information about you, you can ask us to correct any mistakes by, once again, contacting the Customer Services department.

## Links to Other Websites

This privacy notice does not cover the links within this site linking to other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

We keep our privacy notice under regular review. This privacy notice was last updated on 13 June 2013.

## How to Contact Us

Requests for information about our privacy policy can be emailed to the Customer Services department ([customercare@confetti.co.uk](mailto:customercare@confetti.co.uk)) or by writing to:

Customer Services  
Confetti Celebrations Limited  
3rd Floor, Ace Mill  
Gorse Street  
Oldham  
Lancashire  
OL9 9RJ
